higgypop.com 2019-12-29

# Privacy Policy | Higgypop

Higgypop is committed to protecting the rights and respecting the privacy of our users in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and other privacy legislation.

This policy sets out how we will collect information about you through interaction with us through our website and what we will use it for.

Any personal information you provide about yourself to us is voluntary and will only be used in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## What Personal Data We Collect

Personal Data means any information that can identify you as an individual. We need to collect personal information from you in order for you to use certain features on this website.  

This includes but is not limited to, your first name, surname, date of birth, email address, and postal address. Some of these pieces of information are optional. We will not normally collect any sensitive personal information from you. If we do, we will request your explicit prior consent to do so.

We collect your details when you create an account, subscribe to our email newsletter, place an order, submit comments via contact forms, play games, vote or nominate in our awards, vote in polls, chat live, send an email to an email address associated with this website, or enter a competition or promotion.

Some of our website features allow you to invite a contact, such as a friend or family member to use the service. In order to provide this service, we will collect both your personal details and your contact's. We will use your name when we contact the person you have recommended, their personal data will only be used once and will not be saved or stored in any way.

We also collect anonymous data, which doesn't identify you as a person, via Google Analytics. This anonymous statistical information about your use of our website helps us understand how users use our services and features, and enables us to ensure that the content we produce is well received and of interest to our readers.

## Use Of Personal Data

We will always be transparent about how we plan to use your data so that you have the choice whether or not to give it to us.

If you give us consent and have opted to receive communications, then we may use your personal information to communicate with you about our services and promotions, or send you notifications of new content and features which may be of interest to you.

It is not our practice to contact you if you have made it clear that you do not wish to hear from us and you have the right to request that we cease sending communications. You can do this by clicking the unsubscribe link in the emails you receive from us, or by contacting privacy@higgypop.com.

Information, comments and media submitted through contact forms, other interactive elements, or sent to email addresses published on this website may be used in posts, articles or website features. We may also use this data as a testimonial. No identifying personal information, including full name or email address will ever be published as part of this content.

## Data Security

Your data will be stored securely on our server for a reasonable duration in order to smoothly serve content. This may be in the form of cache files, database entries or other server-side storage methods. Data submitted through contact forms will be deleted within 30 days of submission and postal addresses will be deleted once orders have been fulfilled.

Our servers are protected using HTTPS and SSL technology, so whilst your data is in our care we know it's as secure as it can be.

## Sharing Your Personal Data

Your data will not be sold, traded, rented or otherwise passed on to any third-parties, unless you have given us your explicit prior consent. However, we may disclose your personal information to a third-party in order to process your orders, or to arrange the prize fulfilment for competition winners.

We may also disclose personal information about you to comply with applicable laws and when requested to do so by law enforcement agencies or government bodies.

We reserve the right to transfer personal information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer our website. Following such a sale or transfer, you may contact the organisation behind the purchase with any inquiries concerning the processing of that information.

## Cookies

Cookies are small files that are stored by your browser on your device's storage. Each cookie is unique to your web browser and contains a unique identifier.

To deliver a better, more personalised and interactive services and content to you, we use cookies and other similar automated means. This includes persistent cookies, which stay on your device even after you have gone offline.

 **Session Cookies**

Some of these cookies are essential to the running of the website and enable you to use features such as contact forms, sign into the website using your login details, or to make a transaction. These cookies are not stored on your computer and will expire when you close your web browser session.

 **Third-Party Cookies**

We use a selection of third-party tools for monitoring, ad serving and social media sharing. These services use cookies to collect information about how you use our website, such as which pages you visit. All the information collected is anonymous and is only used to help us improve our websites, understand what interests you and measures how engaging our content is.

If you would rather block our cookies, you can change the settings of your device or browser, the "help" option in your browser should tell you how. For more information on cookies, visit www.aboutcookies.org.

## Your Rights

You have the right to see what information we hold about you. You may ask us to make any changes that you consider necessary to ensure the information is accurate, or have your information completely removed from our records. If you want to apply to see the data we hold about you, you can contact us using our contact page or via privacy@higgypop.com.

## Changes To This Privacy Policy

To allow us to improve our services and to comply with changes to the law, we may occasionally need to make changes to our Privacy Policy. It is recommend that you check this policy occasionally so that you are aware of changes. The date of the last revision is visible at the top of this page.
